Tyler Sullens

tcsullens@gmail.com | https://tcsullens.github.io/

Summary

Senior Engineer with 9+ years of technical and people leadership experience across DevOps/Infra/Platform roles building and scaling web applications. Expertise in Kubernetes orchestration, cloud-native architectures, data infrastructure, and developer experience optimization across diverse organizations.

Technical Skills

Programming: Python, Go, Bash, NodeJS, Typescript, Ruby

DevOps/Platform: Kubernetes, Terraform, Docker, ECS, AWS, GCP, ArgoCD, Helm, Ansible

Jenkins, GitHub Actions, Buildkite, CircleCI, Vault, Cloudflare, Akamai,

Elasticsearch/OpenSearch, MySQL, PostgreSQL, DynamoDB, Redis/Valkey, RabbitMQ, SQS

Observability: Prometheus/Grafana, DataDog, New Relic, Honeycomb, Sentry, Open

Telemetry, eBPF

Data: Redshift, Airflow, DBT, Looker, Glue, Debezium, Kafka

Experience

Senior Platform Engineer, Wrapbook – Washington, DC Current Managing and scaling a Rails-based production finance platform, focusing on developer experience, infrastructure management, high volume CI/CD pipelines, and application uptime/stability.

- Completed refactor of application configuration to use the standard Rails environment configuration instead of custom implementation.
- Maintained large-scale self-hosted CI infrastructure (GitHub Actions).
- Integrated ECR Credential Helper to GitHub Actions self-hosted runners to eliminate pipeline re-run failures and improve developer experience.
- Participated in high-impact CI platform migration project, conducting technical evaluation of alternative platforms and leading the design and deployment of Buildkite self-hosted infrastructure.

Senior Infrastructure Engineer II/Tech Lead, Axios – Washington, DC Jan 2022 – Aug 2024

- Managed infrastructure and tooling for NextJs/Django/Go application services powering the Axios website and internal Content Management System.
- Led technical strategy and cross-functional collaboration for adoption of Cloud-Native security platform (Orca), Data Observability platform (MonteCarlo), and migration to GitHub Actions.
- Identified and reduced Kubernetes cluster costs by 50% through right-sizing deployment resources and optimizing EKS node types and scheduling.
- Developed automated tooling and CI/CD workflows for provisioning ephemeral development environments and production deployments, enabling rapid product iteration.
- Managed Cloudflare infrastructure and improved site resiliency to malicious attacks and bot traffic.
- Owned data platform, configuring CI/CD workflows for data infrastructure, managing Redshift clusters, building tooling and establishing standards for Airflow pipelines and DBT, and integrating MonteCarlo to improve observability across the data platform.
- Reduced Data Lake storage costs by 50% by implementing S3 lifecycle management policies.

Senior DevOps Engineer, CoStar – Washington, DC Mar 2021 – Jan 2022

- Migrated CoStar's flagship service to Kubernetes blue/green deployment using Argo Rollouts, ensuring zero-downtime releases for production workloads.
- Dockerized and deployed .NET applications using Azure Pipelines and Helm, improving deployment consistency and reliability.
- Upgraded Kubernetes clusters without downtime through custom Azure DevOps Pipelines and Terraform infrastructure-as-code resources.
- Wrote and maintained custom Azure Pipelines Tasks (Typescript), and optimized existing pipelines.
- Mentored junior team members on DevOps practices and operational excellence, fostering alignment with organizational goals.

Lead DevOps Engineer, FiscalNote – Washington, DC Sep 2019 – Mar 2021

- Guided team transition to agile practices and developed technical strategy and roadmap for infrastructure modernization.
- Improved cross-team communication and visibility by introducing structured sprint reporting processes across engineering teams.
- Automated infrastructure deployments with Terraform/Terragrunt and Ansible, replacing manually deployed EC2 instances and improving application infrastructure stability.
- Built python tool to automated test environment data refresh process, updating 10+ RDS instances in parallel, drastically reducing time and effort involved from multiple days to hours.
- Created React-based infrastructure dashboard displaying real-time health status of 10+ microservices, improving incident response and troubleshooting capabilities.

- Supported engineering efforts to achieve and maintain SOC 2 compliance through infrastructure security improvements.
- Designed modern multi-account AWS architecture with cross-account VPC connectivity using Transit Gateway.

Software Engineer, Elastic Cloud – Washington, DC Feb 2019 – Sep 2019

- Optimized and managed Jenkins workflows responsible for building and publishing Elastic Cloud platform releases for internal and enterprise customers.
- Integrated new Elastic product versions into development environments, ensuring seamless product iteration.
- Supported developer environments and tooling, resolving issues and developing new features.
- Participated in on-call rotation, investigating and resolving production issues with customer Elastic Cloud deployments.

Lead DevOps Engineer, NPR – Washington, DC Mar 2016 – Feb 2019

- Led transformation of traditional operations team to agile DevOps team, expanding team personnel, capabilities and organizational impact.
- Reduced web server deployment times through custom Debian package development and Chef cookbook optimization.
- Built internal infrastructure dashboard (Golang + React) for Chef server management, improving operational visibility.
- Designed and implemented replication-aware load-balancing for MySQL clusters with HAProxy.
- Pioneered infrastructure expansion into AWS, establishing standards best practices for highly-available application deployments.
- Architected and implemented multi-region AWS service architecture with automated failover capabilities, proven effective in production incidents.
- Evolved legacy, "one-shot" deployment process to failure-aware rolling deployments.
- Developed initial Kubernetes environment, enabling the organization's first container-based service deployments.

Education

West Virginia University – BS in Computer Science 2012